Neil Alden Escobin

https://neilalden.github.io/portfolio/ I (+63) 997-644-7771 I escobin.neil@gmail.com

A self starter and proactive developer who enjoys building apps with machine learning models. Has worked on over a dozen projects with clients and research institutions including DOST and UPLB.

Professional Experience

Medicomm Pacific Inc.

Aug 2022 - Present

Junior React Native Developer

Develops new features and improves existing features for multiple mobile apps

University of the Philippines

Oct 2021 - Present

Mobile Developer (Freelancer)

- Designed and developed an online classroom that allows students to participate in activities and quizzes without internet connection. App was developed using React Native and Firebase and is available in Google Play Store here.
 - o Key Features:
 - o Online chat system
 - o Admin portal and and user management
 - o Content management system
 - Quizzes and grading system

Laguna State Polytechnic University

Apr - Jul 2022

Software Developer Intern

- Built a mobile app with machine learning features for DOST (Department of Science and Technology) using React Native and Firebase. View app here.
 - o Key Features:
 - o Monitors and forecasts water quality in Tadlac lake using a machine learning model deployed through Flask API
 - O Visualizes water quality data through a heat map built using Python
- · Assisted set up and tested water sensors used for data gathering
- Re-created an admin web portal written in PHP using NextJS and migrated its database from XLS to PostgreSQL
- Designed the UI/UX of the app

Lotus Golden Circle

Sept 2018 - Nov 2018

Web Developer (Freelancer)

 Designed and developed a content management system using Laravel, SQL and Bootstrap

Other Client Projects

Web/Mobile Developer (Freelancer)

2022

 Crime detection - Real time image recognition (Python, Flask, Tensorflow, Sklearn, Javascript, HTML, CSS)

2022

 Corn Map - Forecasting of crops with mapping (Python, Flask, Tensorflow, Sklearn, Javascript, HTML, CSS) 2022 • Smart Class - Virtual classroom with student grade prediction (Python, Flask,

Tensorflow, Sklearn, React Native, Firebase)

2019 - 2020 • Several POS Systems - CRUD operations and authentication (C#, mySQL)

Education and Certifications

Aug 2018 - Aug 2022 B.S. Computer Science at Laguna State Polytechnic University

Jul 2016 - Jul 2018 Information Communication Technology, STI College Calamba

Jul 2018 Responsive Web Design, FreeCodeCamp

About 300 hours of course work on HTML, CSS, Javascript

Dec 2020 Object Oriented Design, University of Alberta, Coursera

A 4-week course on object-oriented design principles and guidelines

Feb 2021 MIT 6.006 Introduction to Algorithms, MIT Open Courseware

A 24- lecture introduction to mathematical modeling of computational problems

Mar 2021 <u>Javascript Algorithms and Data Structures</u>, FreeCodeCamp

About 300 hours of course work on data structures and algorithms

Awards and Extra Curricular

Sept 2022 Best in Thesis (Cluster-based time series analysis of Covid19 risk in Los Baños)

Sept 2022 Best in On the Job Training

Jul 2022 Best Paper, Student Research Congress, Laguna State Polytechnic University

Dec 2021 Participant, 5th International Research Conference on Innovations and Engineering

Jul 2021 2nd Place, Coding Competition, Laguna State Polytechnic University

Aug 2019 President, Great Innovators of Computer Technology Society

Dec 2018 1st Place, Coding Competition, Laguna State Polytechnic University

2018 - 2022 Scholar, Iskolar ng Laguna